<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Some remarks upon a book, entitled, Christ's lambs defended against Satan's rage, &amp;c. Being the Quakers answer to The Quakers unmask'd &amp;c. : In a letter to E.S., Esq.</title>
            <author>A. C.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1691</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 35 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A90435</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1417C</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R233470</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">45789380</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 45789380</idno>
            <idno type="VID">172690</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A90435)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 172690)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2645:21)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Some remarks upon a book, entitled, Christ's lambs defended against Satan's rage, &amp;c. Being the Quakers answer to The Quakers unmask'd &amp;c. : In a letter to E.S., Esq.</title>
                  <author>A. C.</author>
                  <author>Pennyman, John, 1628-1706.</author>
                  <author>E. S.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for J. Gwillim ... and R. Baldwin ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1691.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed: A. C.</note>
                  <note>Attributed to John Pennyman by Wing.</note>
                  <note>"Licensed, June 19. 1691.:</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Christ Church (University of Oxford). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Whitehead, George, 1636?-1723. --  Christ's lamb defended against Satan's rage.</term>
               <term>Pennyman, John, 1628-1706. --  Quakers unmasked.</term>
               <term>Society of Friends --  England --  Controversial literature.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:172690:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:172690:1"/>
            <head>SOME REMARKS Upon a Book, entitled, <hi>Chriſt's Lambs defended againſt Satan's rage,</hi> &amp;c. Being the <hi>Quakers</hi> Anſwer to <hi>The Quakers Vnmask'd,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <head type="sub">
               <hi>In a Letter to</hi> E. S. <abbr>
                  <hi>Eſq</hi>
               </abbr>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">LICENSED, <hi>June</hi> 19. 1691.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>HAving had the curioſity and opportunity of reading, <hi>
                  <hi>The Quakers Vnmask'd,</hi> Their Double dealing and Falſe-heartedneſs diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered,</hi> &amp;c. I thought it impoſſible for the <hi>Quakers</hi> to vindicate themſelves from that Authors Charge; which made me deſirous to read their Anſwer; and having peruſed it, I can ſcarce forbear to Remark ſome few Paſſages, which are clear Confutations of their boaſted <hi>Innocency, Plainneſs, and Chriſtian Charity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In the Advertiſement to the Reader, <hi>G. Whitehead</hi> takes notice that <hi>The Quakers Vnmask'd,</hi> &amp;c. was ſent them in Manuſcript in the year 1677. and that Liberty of Conſcience being eſtabliſhed by Law, and placed upon the Book in writing, is the cauſe of its now publication. <hi>Which</hi> (ſays <hi>G. W.) looks as if he envyed our preſent Liberty.</hi> Behold the Spirit of this Anſwerer! Mr. <hi>Pennyman</hi> kept his Books unpub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhed for 13 years together, leſt it might be any oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion of the <hi>Quakers</hi> Perſecution; but when Liberty of Conſcience is eſtabliſhed by Law, he publiſheth 10 or 11 of them, preſuming there is now no danger of their being perſecuted. Does this look as if he envyed their preſent Liberty, and not rather that he was glad of it, as no doubt he is.</p>
            <p>In p. 6. to the Reader. <q>Our Adverſary, again p 14. <hi>(ſays he)</hi> deals very unfairly and unjuſtly by <hi>G. W.</hi> about ſome of our Friends, ſaying, They give forth Writings from the immediate Eternal Spirit of God, and by the ſame Spirit and Power that was in the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets, Chriſt, and his Apoſtles; unto which he falſly addeth, And their ſo ſpeaking (G. W. <hi>ſaith</hi>) is of as great Authority as the Scriptures and Chapters are, and greater; his words (and their ſo ſpeaking) are <hi>J. P</hi>'s own Abuſe and Perverſion.</q> Now I beſeech you, Sir, read the Paſſage in p. 14. and ſee wherein <hi>J. P</hi>'s Abuſe and Perverſion lies. It lies in this, that he added theſe words [<hi>and their ſo ſpeaking</hi>] and did not put them in a different Character, to diſtinguiſh them from <hi>G. W's</hi> words, though they did not alter the ſenſe at all; if you leave them out, the Paſſage is as much to the ſame purpoſe, as if they were in. Did ever any Writer charge his Adverſary with Abuſe and Perverſion upon ſo ſlender an account? What an af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>front is it to the ſimple-hearted Reader to write at this rate? This is the Man that in his Letter to <hi>J. O.</hi> threatens Mr. <hi>P. farther to detect and unmask him if he will not be reduced to Chriſtianity.</hi> Does he mean by Chriſtianity, <hi>Quakeriſm,</hi> which it ſeems teaches him to uſe the baſeſt Equivocations and Slights that can be found in any Writer?</p>
            <p>Of his Book, p. 3. <hi>He utterly denies it as a Slan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, that the</hi> Quakers <hi>formerly exhorted Men to fight and would fight themſelves.</hi> I muſt refer you to <hi>The Quakers Vnmask'd,</hi> &amp;c. to judge whether that is a Slander, or not? It will abundantly ſatisfie you, whilſt you underſtand their Writings in the plain ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt ſenſe of the Words without their after Equivo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations. <hi>J. P</hi> cites one of the, <hi>Quakers</hi> Miniſters, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>We directed all People to the Spirit of God in them, and if that led them to fight, I had nothing a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt it;</hi> for this, ſaith <hi>G. W.</hi> he quotes, fol. 4. but tells us not what Book. But why did he not tell <hi>J. P</hi> ſo 13 years ago when he deſired to know what Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rors they ſound in the Quotations, (if there were any; however to ſatisfie him that it was a true citation, he took it out of the <hi>Quakers</hi> Book, where Foreign Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters were recorded, which was firſt in <hi>J. O</hi>'s cuſtody and afterwards in <hi>J. P</hi>'s.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P.</hi> 4. The <hi>Quakers</hi> tell <hi>Rich.</hi> Protector, 'That he would walk with the Lord, and preſerve his Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, then thy Name ſhall be greater than was thy
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:172690:2"/>Fathers, and the numberleſs number of this [Now] diſtreſſed People will be unto thee a ſtrength, and ſtand by thee, and <hi>Defend thee and thy juſt Government.</hi> Sir, If you had been Protector, I perſuade my ſelf, you would have thought theſe People would have fought to defend you and your Government: But whatever they or you thought then, the meaning now is, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to <hi>G. W. &amp;c.</hi> they would defend him and his Government, <hi>By Righteouſneſs, Prayers, and Faith, and by Contributions, Taxes,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>or the fear of the Lord,</hi> as in the days of <hi>Jehoſaphat.</hi> Would you not judge that Man perjured, that ſhould ſwear Allegiance in ſuch terms, with ſuch a meaning? And muſt we not take the <hi>Quakers</hi> words for as binding as an Oath?</p>
            <p>Next, <hi>p.</hi> 5. you will pleaſe to note what <hi>G.W.</hi> An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwers to the Charge of <hi>upbraiding others with that which themſelves, for many years, were as deeply concerned and ingaged in,</hi> &amp;c. <q>To all which, ſaith <hi>G. W.</hi> I do conſcientiouſly Anſwer, He hath moſt groſly and palpably belyed the People cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>Quakers</hi> in theſe Paſſages divers ways. Firſt, in rendring them, without exception of Perſons, not only Juſtifiers of the late Wars, and what had been done therein, without exception of things done, but alſo equally concerned with the <hi>Presbyterians, Inde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendents,</hi> and others therein.</q> But do the <hi>Quakers</hi> when they charge theſe things upon the <hi>Presbyte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rians,</hi> &amp;c. make any exception of Perſons or Things? And yet it is well known, and it is proved out of their own writings in <hi>The Quakers Vnmask'd,</hi> &amp;c. that their Chief Leaders approved of the greateſt things done in the late Wars againſt the King, and to his Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon; whereas the Presbyterians generally diſ-ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved of them. Beſides they ſay, <hi>their giving forth Papers or Printed Books, is from the immediate eternal Spirit of God,</hi> and that <hi>their Preachers are guided by an Infallible Spirit, and that they are of one Mind and Judgment,</hi> and the like; and therefore an indefinite, and general charge will affect them more generally than other Parties.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>G. W.</hi> ſays, p. 6. <q>The War began in 41. and in 48 the King was Beheaded, and all this while no <hi>Quakers</hi> heard of, till about 50.51, 52. when there was no Wars in <hi>England</hi> for them to be concerned in, how falſe then is <hi>J P.</hi> to ſay, The <hi>Quakers</hi> were as much, or more, concerned in the War againſt the King as any others.</q> But <hi>G. W.</hi> confeſſes, that <hi>di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers who have been ſince, and now of us,</hi> [Quakers,] <hi>have formerly been concerned in the late Wars.</hi> And <hi>J. P.</hi> has made evident their approbation of what was then done, and that many that turned <hi>Quakers</hi> in the Armies, continued there till they were turned out, that the Protector is blamed for putting them out by G. <hi>Fox</hi> and others, that they are called, <hi>Sober Men and true Hearts that feared God and trembled at His Word, valiant Captains, Soldiers, and Officers, it may be for ſaying thou to a ſingle Perſon, or for wearing their Hats,</hi> &amp;c. the diſtinguiſhing Characters of <hi>Quakers</hi> from others. Whereas, he ſays, there was no Wars in <hi>England</hi> in 50.51.52. it is a piece of his cunning, and is falſe; for <hi>Worceſter</hi> Fight was in the year 51. and Sir <hi>George Booth</hi>'s Inſurrection in 1659. when the <hi>Quakers</hi> gave intelligence, calling them Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels, for but endeavouring to bring in the King; and for ſome years there were Wars both in <hi>Scotland</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and upon the Sea, and in <hi>Flanders.</hi> See <hi>E. Burrough</hi>'s <hi>Alarm Sounded,</hi> &amp;c. 1659. <hi>The Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers Vnmask'd,</hi> &amp;c. p. 6. 9. You ſee then how <hi>G. W</hi>'s Anſwer is both falſe and deceitful</p>
            <p>P. 7. 8. <hi>G. VV.</hi> charges <hi>J. P.</hi> with an apparent lye, in ſaying, the <hi>Quakers</hi> had been engaged in the ſame Cauſe, ſo as <hi>to Preach up Battels,</hi> &amp;c. But I pray Sir, what difference is there between Preaching up Battles, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and exhorting Generals, Officers, and Soldiers, to go forth againſt mighty Enemies till they had ſubdued them, and ſet up their Standard a top of <hi>Rome,</hi> and done many other things which were to be done by Fighting? And that in the <hi>Quakers</hi> Spirit. See <hi>E. B's Alarm Sounded,</hi> &amp;c. p 28.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P</hi> 9, 10. <hi>G.W.</hi> Commends the <hi>Quakers</hi> for their for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bearance towards <hi>J. P. and is confident that had</hi> J. P. <hi>look'd upon them as Fighters,</hi> &amp;c <hi>he durſt not have adventured to have given them ſuch frequent and publick occaſions of provocations and frequent diſturbances and interruptions.</hi> To this, <hi>J. P.</hi> ſaith, he hath always been careful never to interrupt them, nor to give them any diſturbance otherwiſe than by ſpeaking a few words, either before they began to Preach, or when any one of them had done Preaching; and though the words which he ſpoke they could not gainſay, but were true; yet becauſe they look'd upon t, that in what he ſpake he meant them therefore (notwithſtanding his peaceable behaviour) he has ſometimes found himſelf in much danger from the <hi>Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers,</hi> who have frequently done violence to him them ſelves, and that in the place where he has a Propriety.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P.</hi> 10. They would excuſe <hi>G. Fox</hi> in what he ſays againſt an <hi>Earthly King,</hi> &amp;c. by turning it into an <hi>Earthly oppreſſing King, and ſetting an Earthly King over them,</hi> p. 11. But did not King <hi>Charles</hi> the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond (to whom they addreſſed ſo early, profeſſing their Innocency formerly, and their preſent Truth and Fidelity to him) challenge the Supreme Power over the Church? <hi>Are not all theſe Elders Chriſtians, that will dote ſo much of an Earthly King</hi> Traytors a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Chriſt? ſays <hi>G. Fox;</hi> And whom did they dote upon but <hi>Charles</hi> 2 (and afterwards upon King <hi>James</hi>) whom the <hi>Quakers</hi> do now <hi>love, own, and honour?</hi> Neither do you read, ſaith <hi>G. F. that there ever was an Earthly King ſince the days of the Apoſtles, but
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:172690:2"/>amongſt the Apoſtate Chriſtians.</hi> So then according to their own Principle, when King <hi>Charles</hi> 2. was among the <hi>Quakers</hi> he was among Apoſtate Chriſtians; or elſe they temporiz'd and changed their Principles, holding that there might be an <hi>Earthly King</hi> among true Chriſtians. And how could they profeſs their Innocency to the King, and that none had any juſt cauſe againſt them, ſince they had maintained ſuch Principles as aforeſaid? The caſe of the Prophet <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>muel</hi> was far different from that of the <hi>Quakers,</hi> he was chief Magiſtrate himſelf, and they a little part of a People that had put to Death their King, and kept out the Heir by Arms, (of both which the <hi>Quakers</hi> ſufficiently approved.) Now, ſuppoſe, <hi>Samuel</hi> had been the Repreſentative of the <hi>Quakers,</hi> and the Heir made King contrary to his mind and endeavour, would he have addreſſed him, and ſaid. <q>You are not ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted, O King, with my Principle and Practice, neither have known my Innocency and Sufferings, they that ſpeak againſt me as a Perſon that was an Oppoſer of your Kingſhip, and did vehemently ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hort the People from ſubjecting themſelves to your Arbitrary and Oppreſſive Power, had no juſt ground for that Charge. I love, own, and honour you and your Government.</q> Might not the King have an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer'd him, Are not you aſham'd, <hi>Samuel,</hi> to play the Hypocrite in this groſs manner? Do you brag of <hi>your Principle, and Practice, and Innocency</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore me in this matter, ſince if the People had acted according to your Principle, and done as you would have had them, I ſhould never have recovered my Kingdoms? If you are innocent, who is guilty? Is this your Innocent Plainneſs? Who then is Equivoca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting and Deceitful? Your Pride will not ſuffer you to acknowledge any Error in Principle or Practice, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe ye have profeſs'd to ſpeak and write from the immediate Eternal Spirit of GOD, though you are found fallible and fooliſh as other Men.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P.</hi> 15. <hi>The Quakers Vnmask'd,</hi> is cited, ſaying, <hi>Are not they in their own Judgments become Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates, for now they ſay we love, own, and honour an Earthly King. G. W.</hi> anſwers, p. 16. <hi>And where do we uſe theſe very words</hi> Earthly King <hi>on this occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, but that we love, own, and honour the King, (whom here this Mau has judged an Earthly King,) does this ſhew us to be Apoſtates. Remark</hi> Did you ever read a more frivolous Anſwer? Was it any other King but that very King <hi>Charles</hi> 2. whom they had writ ſo bitterly againſt, under the Name of an <hi>Earth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly King?</hi> he was an <hi>Earthly King</hi> before, when they ſaid, <hi>They were Traytors againſt Chriſt that will dote ſo much on an Earthly King;</hi> but now the <hi>Quakers</hi> love, own, and honour him, he ſhall not be called an <hi>Earthly King.</hi> He was an <hi>Earthly King</hi> before when the <hi>Epiſcopals</hi> and <hi>Presbyterians</hi> doted on him; but now he is become the <hi>Quakers</hi> King he muſt be ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what elſe; I preſume not a Heavenly King; but this is ſomewhat of the <hi>Quakers</hi> plainneſs.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P.</hi> 19. <hi>G.W.</hi> ſays, <q>I am perſuaded that reproving him [<hi>O. C.</hi> Protector] for putting ſuch [as feared GOD, ſober Men and true Hearts, becauſe of their faithfulneſs to the LORD,] out of the Army for their Conſciences, was MORE upon his breach of Promiſe, than with an intent to have them always continue in it, in order to War and Fight.</q> Here <hi>G. W.</hi> or whoever writ this paſſage, would ſeem to have ſome ſenſe of Conſcience; for his ſaying MORE is a comparative with what follows; and argues that it was written with an intent to have had them al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways to continue in the Army in order to War and Fight, <hi>though MORE upon his breach of Promiſe.</hi> I doubt we ſhall not find <hi>G. W. &amp;c.</hi> guilty of ſo much openneſs again throughout the whole Book. Do not the <hi>Quakers</hi> hold that none fear GOD truly and right<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly but themſelves? <hi>That they are in the Truth, and none but they; and only among them is GOD known?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Chriſt was not contradictory to himſelf in bidding his Diſciples to ſell their Garments, and buy Swords, and conſequently to wear Swords (as <hi>Peter</hi> did,) be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe He ſaith my Kingdom is not of this World, or from hence; but Chriſt was contradictory to the <hi>Quakers</hi> ſenſe of that ſaying, becauſe if it was not law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful to Fight, in any caſe, Chriſt would never have bid them buy Swords: But I did not intend to argue the lawfulneſs of Fighting, only <hi>G. W.</hi> brings it in need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſy.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P.</hi> 21. One of their chiefeſt Preachers had ſaid, <hi>It is no Rebellion to call away thoſe in Power;</hi> by which <hi>J. P.</hi> underſtands to Depoſe <hi>thoſe in Power that perform not their Truſt: G. W.</hi> calls this a per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe addition of a meaning, <hi>as if to</hi> call away <hi>and to</hi> Depoſe <hi>were both one in common acceptance.</hi> But <hi>G. W.</hi> is not pleaſed to tell us what other thing was meant by it, and I am perſuaded that no Man but a fore-warn'd <hi>Quaker</hi> will take them for other than both one.</p>
            <p>But I muſt haſten; read his 23 page, and you will find it amount to this, <hi>Had you</hi> [the Army] <hi>been faithful to the Power of the LORD GOD, you had gon into</hi> Spain <hi>to require the Blood of the Innocent, —and knock'd at</hi> Rome <hi>Gates,</hi> &amp;c. [And done wonderful great things by wicked and unchriſtian Fighting, or otherwiſe by the fear and terror of your Power, Arms, and Conqueſts without Fighting,] <hi>or as the Hoſt of the</hi> Midianites <hi>fled and were overcome.</hi> and yet not by Fighting <hi>on</hi> Gideon<hi>'s part, but by a mean Stratagem. Quere,</hi> Whether they that kill by Stratagem do not Fight? And when the <hi>Ephraimites</hi> ſlew <hi>Oreb</hi> and <hi>Zeeb,</hi> and brought their Heads to <hi>Gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deon,</hi> and purſued <hi>Midian,</hi> they did not Fight?
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:172690:3"/>
               <hi>Judges.</hi> 7.25. And whether <hi>Barack, Jepthah, Sam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, David, Samuel,</hi> and the Prophets, who by Faith ſubdued Kingdoms, and turned to flight the Armies of the Aliens did not Fight? <hi>G.W.</hi> has found out all theſe ways of an Army's Conquering without Fighting. Sir, I know you are an impartial Man, can you think ſeriouſly (not that any Man to whom the <hi>Quakers</hi> wrote, or any Man that ſhould read what they wrote, would underſtand them in any ſuch ſenſe, without Fighting; for I take it for manifeſt no Man did; but) whether they that wrote, or even the <hi>Quakers</hi> themſelves, (till now they are preſs'd with theſe paſſages,) ever thought of ſuch Senſes? And if not, where is the <hi>Quakers</hi> plainneſs, whereof they ſo nau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeouſly boaſt?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>P.</hi> 24. <hi>G. W.</hi> ſays, <hi>It cannot conſiſt with our Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtian Principle, ſo much as to avenge our ſelves.</hi> Who are more ready to avenge themſelves in Word and Print than <hi>Quakers?</hi> How have they railed and reviled their Oppoſers? Witneſs thoſe Names <hi>G. W.</hi> calls <hi>Will. Rogers, F. Bugg, Tho. Criſp</hi> and others, in the Preface to his Book, <hi>Judgment fixed,</hi> viz. <hi>Apoſtate-Informers, Treacherous Hypocrites, Falſe Brethren, and Deceitful Workers, Betraying Judas's, Devils Incarnate, who having toſt their firſt love to Truth, and gone out from us, are become degenerate, without Natural Affections, Dogs that are without, Wolves, and raging waves of the Sea, that foam out their own ſhame.</hi> And a multitude of other ſuch like Names do they call thoſe that oppoſe, and cannot con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form to their outward Preſcriptions and Impoſitions, beſides their frequent violence with their own Hands,
<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <p>See the complaint of one of their own People, touching this matter,</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>It hath been their lot to be haled, (with violence) out of the Aſſemblies,— Did I think to ſee the ſame violence offered in our Aſſemblies! Nay, but with Sorrow, mine Eyes have ſeen pulling down, haling out, and thruſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing forth of our Meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, and they went to the utmoſt, as far as their Power; and doubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs they wanted not Will but Power to puniſh.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>And although they e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>xerciſe the Oppreſſions before-mentioned,</hi> (and much more as may be ſeen in the ſaid Book;) <hi>yet by their deceitful flatteries, they make People believe, That they are <hi>harmleſs, inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent,</hi> and <hi>peaceable Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, ſuffering and bearing wrong but not doing any.</hi> And if any Perſon write, or ſpeak their Grief, they will repreſent them under ſuch terms as may render them odious; and the more effectually to weaken their Teſtimonies they will fix upon them ſcurrilous and contem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptible Appellations, as <hi>Scotch-Men, Welch men, Tinker, Taylor,</hi>
                     </hi> &amp;c. <hi>Some of them utterly un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>true; and to prevent an Inquiſition into the mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, they would make People believe, that they are <hi>envious, malicious, and diſcompoſed Spirits, bad, dirty, factions, and ranting Spirits, who are gone from Truth, and are out of Truth.</hi> Such is the Portion of thoſe that appear in the leaſt againſt their imperious, tyrannical, and laſcivious Actions: And whatever Man detected the Falla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies, and deſtructive Cheats of imperious, diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dainful Men, but was thus reproached?</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Muſt it be Juſtice in them to complain of their Oppreſſions; and Envy, and Malice,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>in us to complain of ours? Their years are but few; yet verily they have been exceeding expert to learn of the Papiſts, Subtilties.</hi> Spirit of the Hat, <hi>p.</hi> 29, 36, 37.</p>
               </note> and what is a great part of this Book of <hi>G W. &amp;c.</hi> but avenging themſelves of <hi>J. P.?</hi> They might have ſaid all they had to ſay in their own vindica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, without thoſe ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifold reproaches, and even Curſes, which they belch out againſt him, ſuch as that in p. 30 <hi>God will ſmite thee, thou malicious Hypocrite. Our Innocency ſhall riſe up in Judgment againſt thee.</hi> Read to the end of that Paragraph. Of this nature is <hi>G. W.</hi> glorying, that <hi>Jer. Ives not long af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter his malicious Works againſt us</hi> [Quakers] <hi>was ſoon cut off by Death,</hi> p. 33.</p>
            <p>I muſt deſire you, Sir, to read p. 34, 35, 36, 37. of their Vindication of that Declaration to which Mr. <hi>P</hi>—'s Name was amongſt the reſt ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed, and then judge what <hi>diſingenuity and deceit</hi> there was in him, to inſert the ſubſtance of that Declaration, without telling that his own Name was to it, ſince his Name was not to thoſe after Declarations, which are inconſiſtent with this. 2. Whether it is poſſible to give a more Equivocating An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer to any charge, than <hi>G. W. &amp;c.</hi> has given of this? They ſay, <hi>God might command Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands and Ten Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands of His Saints, at this Day, to Fight in His own Cauſe</hi>
               <note n="†" place="margin">
                  <hi>This paſſage, and the like, the</hi> Quakers <hi>left out in the reprint of</hi> E. B<hi>'s works, know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing (it ſeems) they would expoſe them in their clear ſenſe; but being brought to light, they then ſtudy to put an equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vocal ſenſe on them.</hi>
               </note>. But <hi>it muſt not be taken for granted</hi> (ſays <hi>G. W.</hi>) <hi>that therefore he would do it.</hi> But that which GOD may do, and which <hi>we cannot yet be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that He will make uſe of us in that way,</hi> and therefore <hi>for the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent we are given up to bear and ſuffer,</hi> &amp;c We muſt needs conclude that this is one of thoſe things that GOD hath made no DECREE to the contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, but that He may Will it to be done, even by us in the future, though He hath not done it at preſent. And all that <hi>G. W. &amp;c.</hi> has Cri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticiz'd upon the Equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vocalneſs of the term YET, does but bewray his and their Equivoca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; for though YET may be taken for Never<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theleſs, when they ſay,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:172690:3"/>but YET His Kingdom <hi>is not of this World;</hi> notwithſtanding it cannot be ſo taken, when they ſay, <hi>neither can we YET be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve,</hi> &amp;c. but it muſt be taken to denote the time to this preſent <hi>[adhuc, as yet]</hi> in exception to the time to come; eſpecially when it is farther ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plained by the clauſe, <hi>for the preſent;</hi> which is ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſarily oppoſed to the time to come, and imports clearly that Fighting may be commanded as in the Future, as now bearing and ſuffering is commanded. I am very confident that <hi>G. W. &amp;c.</hi> cannot produce any one inſtance out of any Man's Writings, that underſtood well the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Tongue, of the uſe of the term <hi>Yet,</hi> in ſuch a Phraſe and Conſtruction, in any other ſenſe than of <hi>Time.</hi> But if all uncon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd Readers muſt and will underſtand it in this ſenſe, then <hi>G. W's</hi> Anſwer is full of groſs Equivo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation.</p>
            <p>Theſe are the People that exalt themſelves above all other Profeſſors whatſoever, that they reckon all them to be of the World, out of the Truth; and them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves <hi>the Only People of GOD, and that they are in the Truth, and none but they, Chriſt's Lambs,</hi> and the like. And for diſtinguiſhing themſelves from o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, they took up ſome Obſervances, or Ceremonies, which did it effectually; ſuch as ſaying <hi>Thou</hi> not <hi>You</hi> to a ſingle Perſon; calling no Man <hi>Maſter,</hi> but <hi>John</hi> or <hi>Thomas, &amp;c.</hi> not <hi>I thank you,</hi> but <hi>I receive thy love;</hi> not carrying the Feet but the Head foremoſt of their Dead, and the like. They condemn utterly the courteſie of putting off the Hat to any. In ſhort, they affected ſingularity in moſt things that were cuſtoma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry in <hi>England,</hi> how innocent ſoever: And under the notion of not Swearing, they only refuſe the Ceremo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of an Oath, as the laying the Hand upon, and Kiſſing the Book. Now, I pray Sir, what of true Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion, or real Goodneſs, is there in theſe things? Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe the whole World did obſerve them, would they be at all the better for it? However, by theſe things they have cut off all others, how religious and ſincere ſoever. And if any Man oppoſe what they ſay or do, inſtead of meekly anſwering, they are ready with the moſt virulent, opprobrious, and threatning Language and Writings that can be found in any ſort whatever. They will diligently ſeek out, and take up any thing may reproach one; and will inſinuate Crimes that Men are moſt free from: Thus have they changed the Meekneſs and Gentleneſs of Chriſtianity, into Fierceneſs and Churliſhneſs; Humility and Modeſty, into Arrogance and Self-conceit; Peaceableneſs into Contentiouſneſs; Mildneſs into Clamour; and Bleſſing into evil ſpeaking and reviling; Plainneſs and Simpli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>city, into Equivocation and Craft; and all this under the Profeſſion of the moſt unſpotted Innocency and Sincerity. Truth, Righteouſneſs, and Holineſs.</p>
            <p>But I would not be underſtood to impute theſe Immoralities to the <hi>Quakers</hi> in general, nor to all their Teachers and Leading Men, but to the <hi>Foxonian</hi> Party that love to Govern and have the Preheminence, who have endeavoured to ſuppreſs thoſe who have at any time propoſed any thing contrary to their Sentiments. Thus in a few years, inſtead of being led and guided, and being obedient every one to the Light in himſelf, they were obliged to ſubmit to the ſenſe of the greater number of the Governing BODY, though never ſo contrary to their own ſenſe. Nay, this Impoſing Spirit proceeded ſo far, at a Quarterly Meeting in <hi>Barbadoes,</hi> where they did not act with that Caution and Cunning as here at <hi>London,</hi> that they made and ſubſcribed this following Order, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <q>I deſire to give up my whole Concern, if required, both <hi>Spiritual</hi> and <hi>Temporal</hi> unto the Spirit of <hi>God</hi> in Men and Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men's Meetings, as believing it to be more according to the Univerſal Wiſdom of <hi>God,</hi> than any particular meaſure in my ſelf, or any particulars with whom the Men and Women's Meetings have not Unity.</q>
            </p>
            <p>The Actings, Writings, and Speakings of that kind I have ſpoken of, being obſerved by ſome
<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>W. Rogers, T. Criſp, F. Bugg, W. Macklow, J. Story, J. Wilkinſon, Charles Harris, J. Rance, Tho. Curtis, J. Anſloe,</hi> and many more.</note> among them, who were either too wiſe, or too honeſt to be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuaded, that thoſe cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt Fruits could pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed either from the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of God, or from the Light within, that they griev'd and mourn'd to ſee that excellent Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciple of Reformation, <hi>The Light in every Man,</hi> ſo groſly perverted and undermined, that they were made to oppoſe and teſtifie againſt them.</p>
            <p>Sir, I might go on throughout <hi>G. W.</hi>'s <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whole Book, and ſhew many more groſs Equivocations, Palliations, and Deceits; but I will not proceed far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, leſt I may ſeem to queſtion your Judgment, in not obſerving thoſe things that are ſo evident. But I think we that read Books have juſt cauſe of in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dignation againſt thoſe <hi>Quakers,</hi> who have the face to impoſe upon the World ſuch abominable Stuff, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Notion of the Teachings of the Light, of
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:172690:4"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:172690:4"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:172690:5"/>the unſpotted Innocency and Chriſtian ſincerity. But it may reaſonably be thought they write not for vindication of themſelves to thoſe that are of the World, (as they call all that are not in their Form;) but for their own Party, that are ſo blindly addicted to their Leaders, that they ſwallow every thing they ſay without conſideration: Unhappy Men! that have given up their Minds to the Glory of a ſingular Party, in contempt of all others, and can find no other way of vindicating themſelves. I may need your excuſe for writing ſo much, and therefore will now ſubſcribe</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Sir,</salute> 
               <signed> Yours A. C.</signed>
               <dateline>
                  <date>
                     <hi>May</hi> 23. 1691.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <head>POSTSCRIPT.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>AND beſides what I ſaid about Fighting, I am credibly informed, that ſome <hi>Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers</hi> have not only fought, but that with great Courage and Magnanimity. The firſt I ſhall mention is Mr. <hi>William Mead</hi> an eminent Perſon, who being ſet upon by three High-way-men, and having only a Cudgel, or Staff, in his Hand, did not only bravely defend himſelf therewith, but knock'd down one of the Robbers ſo wounded, that the other were forced to carry him away, whilſt Mr. <hi>Mead</hi> eſcaped their Hands. The next ſhall be one <hi>Matthew Renſhaw</hi> (Maſter of a Ship,) who fought both with great and ſmall Guns, till he was overpowered by the <hi>Turks.</hi> Another, one <hi>John Thompſon,</hi> who fought exceeding ſtoutly, and killed a great many Men before he was taken by the Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my. Theſe two Maſters were not only <hi>Quakers</hi> themſelves, but their Owners gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally, if not every one, ſuch. More might be named, but theſe ſuffice to ſhew that the <hi>Quakers</hi> will fight in a juſt Cauſe, and that ſtoutly too; which puts me in mind again of <hi>G. Fox To the Council of Officers,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>p.</hi> 5. who ſays (of thoſe that had been put out of the Army for being <hi>Quakers,) Of whom it hath been ſaid among you, that they had rather have had one of them than</hi> 7 <hi>Men, and could have turned one of them to ſeven Men.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And ſince my writing the above, I have ſpoken with Mr. <hi>Pennyman</hi> touching the Accuſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion againſt <hi>Stephen Criſp,</hi> mentioned in <hi>The Quakers Unmask'd,</hi> folio p. 14. and which in their <hi>Anſwer,</hi> p. 14. they ſay, <hi>Steph. Criſp abſolutely denies, that he either forced him, or that the Party did ſhew any diſſatisfaction before he Signed and Sealed the ſaid Paper.</hi> Oh! what ſhall we ſay to theſe Men, who not only uſe Equivocatious in their Writings, but do abſolutely deny matter of Fact? to which Mr. <hi>Pennyman</hi> was an Eye and Ear-Witneſs, and is ready to atteſt it, if called thereto; but would not then ſubſcribe as a Witneſs, being greatly diſſatisfied with the unworthineſs of the demand.</p>
            <p>I will add here ſomething concerning the Nature of an Oath, whereby it may appear that the <hi>Quakers</hi> are miſtaken about it.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="explanation">
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:172690:5"/>
            <head>Of the Nature of an Oath.</head>
            <p>WHen the Author to the <hi>Hebrews</hi> ſays (<hi>Ch.</hi> 6.16.) <hi>Men verily Swear by the greater; and an Oath for Confirmation is to them an end of all ſtrife;</hi> he plainly ſhews us, that an Oath is the greateſt and utmoſt Evidence of Truth and Sincerity that can be given; for if a Man openly appeals to GOD, who ſearcheth the Heart, and therefore knows not only what is outward in Men's Words and Actions, but their moſt inward thoughts, that Man gives the utmoſt aſſurance he can poſſibly give; for he that falſifies in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of Men, calling them for Witneſſes, who know the matter, and whoſe office it is to iudge and puniſh, incurs all that reproach, infamy and other puniſhments, which ſo great an offence and abuſe deſerves: So he that falſifies in the preſence of God, calling Him for Witneſs, incurs the greateſt puniſhments of Divine Vengeance, as one that makes God Almighty a Partner and Confederate to a Lie, preſumptuouſly and to his very face. So that however God perhaps is not expreſly invocated to do vengeance upon him, yet in appealing to God as a Witneſs, that is implyed, becauſe He is ſuch a Witneſs as is alſo the Supreme Judge, whoſe Juſtice and Truth is herein appealed to. Therefore calling God to Witneſs is as much an Oath as any other form of Words, as having as much evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence and aſſurance as any other Form whatever, and as great Penalties attending it. Now to aſſert any thing in the preſence of Men expreſly, is all one as to call them for Witneſſes: So alſo to aſſert any thing in the preſence of God expreſly, is all one as to call God for Witneſs.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath">
            <head>
               <hi>Farther ſee ſeveral Forms of an Oath.</hi> viz.</head>
            <p>I <hi>Do hereby testifie in the Truth of my Heart, and in the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of HIM that knoweth all things, and in the Preſence of theſe Faithful Witneſſes,</hi>
               <note n="*" place="margin">[The Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers Form.] See <hi>Q <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nm.</hi> folio, <hi>p.</hi> 14.</note> &amp;c. Or, <hi>GOD is my Witneſs. I call GOD to record on my Soul. The GOD and Father of our LORD Jeſus Chriſt knows that I lye not. GOD is Witneſs between me and thee.</hi> Any of which (or the like) without laying the Hand on the Book, or other Cere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony, or more Words, is not only an Oath, but, [as ſaith a knowing, ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicious, and worthy Perſon,] if Authorized by Act of Parliament, is as much a <hi>Legal Oath</hi> as any now in uſe amongſt us.</p>
            <p>And as the <hi>Quakers</hi> have been miſtaken about an Oath, ſo they have been about their paying of Taxes, in that they allow'd and paid the <hi>Royal Aid</hi> Tax, and that of carrying on the War againſt the <hi>Dutch,</hi> and the like; yet they would not pay towards the Trained Bands, notwithſtanding they are chiefly intended for a Defence; and the other, not only to Defend but to offend our Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, as the Government ſees cauſe. So that 'tis plain, the Tax they then re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſed was more juſtifiable than that they allowed and paid, inaſmuch as to De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend is more allowable and juſtifiable than to Offend.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>J. Gwillim</hi> over againſt the <hi>Great James</hi> in <hi>Biſhops-gate-ſtreet,</hi> and <hi>R. Baldwin</hi> in <hi>Warwick-lane,</hi> 1691.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
